A Guide to the Scrapbooks of the Virginia Dept. of Alcoholic Beverage Control, 1934-1986
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
Scrapbooks of the Virginia Dept. of Alcoholic Beverage Control 1934-1986
The Library of Virginia
44542
48 volumes
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open to research.
Acquisition Information
Transferred 2009
Biographical Information
The Alcoholic Beverage Control Board and its administrative arm, the Department of Alcoholic Beverage Control, were created by an act of the General Assembly passed on March 7, 1934. The act, known as the Alcoholic Beverage Control Act, which the department was established to administer, specified the circumstances under which alcoholic beverages could be purchased and consumed. The act has been amended over the years. A major change occurred on February 7, 1968, when the General Assembly approved the sale of mixed drinks on a local option basis. The Board has three members appointed by the governor and confirmed by the General Assembly. It establishes rules and policies governing the Department, which controls through licenses and permits, the manufacture, bottling, selling, advertising, and transporting of alcoholic beverages; operates state stores for the sale of beverages, other than beer, to consumers and licensees. The Commissioner operates out of the Richmond office, with district offices established in Abingdon, Alexandria, Charlottesville, Chesapeake, Hampton, Lynchburg, Roanoke, and Staunton.
Scope and Content
Collection consists of scrapbooks containing newspaper clippings related to the work and people of the Virginia Dept. of Alcoholic Beverage Control.
Arrangement
Arranged chrologically by beginning date of contents of volume.
Contents List
- Scrapbook. General Clippings 1934 Mar - 1934 July (Volume 1)
- Scrapbook. Violations 1934 Mar 22 - 1941 Jan 1 (Volume 2)
- Scrapbook. Editorials 1934 Mar 22 - 1934 Sept 19 (Volume 3)
- Scrapbook. Letters to the Editor and Out of State 1934 Mar 26 - 1934 Sept 28 (Volume 4)
- Scrapbook. General Clippings 1934 June 22 - 1934 Oct 1 (Volume 5)
- Scrapbook. Editorials 1934 Sept 13 - 1938 Dec 12 (Volume 6)
- Scrapbook. General Clippings 1934 Sept 27 - 1937 Feb 15 (Volume 7)
- Scrapbook. General Clippings 1937 Feb 1 - 1945 (Volume 8)
- Scrapbook. General Clippings 1937 Feb 16 - 1940 July 17 (Volume 9)
- Scrapbook. General Clippings 1938 Dec - 1955 Mar (Volume 10)
- Scrapbook. General Clippings 1940 Aug - 1946 Feb (Volume 11)
- Scrapbook. General Clippings 1941 Jan 30 - 1942 Nov 30 (Volume 12)
- Scrapbook. General Clippings 1946 Mar 1 - 1955 May 12 (Volume 13)
- Scrapbook. General Clippings 1955 May 24 - 1960 Feb 18 (Volume 14)
- Scrapbook. General Clippings 1960 Feb 10 - 1961 Nov 29 (Volume 15)
- Scrapbook. General Clippings 1961 Nov 1963 May (Volume 16)
- Scrapbook. General Clippings 1962 Sept - 1963 Mar (Volume 17)
- Scrapbook. General Clippings 1963 June - 1965 Jan (Volume 18)
- Scrapbook. General Clippings 1965 Feb - 1967 Nov (Volume 19)
- Scrapbook. General Clippings 1966 Jan - 1972 Dec (Volume 20)
- Scrapbook. General Clippings 1967 Dec 1967 Sept (Volume 21)
- Scrapbook. General Clippings 1968 July 10 - 1968 Dec 22 (Volume 22)
- Scrapbook. General Clippings 1969 Jan - 1969 Aug (Volume 23)
- Scrapbook. General Clippings 1969 Sept - 1970 Feb (Volume 24)
- Scrapbook. General Clippings 1970 Feb - 1970 May (Volume 25)
- Scrapbook. General Clippings 1970 Aug - 1971 Feb (Volume 26)
- Scrapbook. General Clippings 1971 Mar - 1971 Dec (Volume 27)
- Scrapbook. General Clippings 1972 Jan - 1972 Apr (Volume 28)
- Scrapbook. General Clippings 1972 May - 1972 Dec (Volume 29)
- Scrapbook. General Clippings 1973 (Volume 30)
- Scrapbook. General Clippings 1974 (Volume 31)
- Scrapbook. General Clippings 1975 (Volume 32)
- Scrapbook. General Clippings 1976 (Volume 1976)
- Scrapbook. General Clippings 1977 Jan - 1977 June (Volume 34)
- Scrapbook. General Clippings 1977 July - 1977 Dec (Volume 35)
- Scrapbook. General Clippings 1978 Jan - 1978 June (Volume 36)
- Scrapbook. General Clippings 1978 July - 1978 Dec (Volume 37)
- Scrapbook. General Clippings 1978 July - 1978 Dec (Volume 38)
- Scrapbook. General Clippings 1979 Jan - 1979 June (Volume 39)
- Scrapbook. General Clippings 1979 July - 1979 Dec (Volume 40)
- Scrapbook. General Clippings 1980 Jan - 1980 June (Volume 41)
- Scrapbook. General Clippings 1980 July - 1980 Dec (Volume 42)
- Scrapbook. General Clippings 1981 (Volume 43)
- Scrapbook. General Clippings 1982 (Volume 44)
- Scrapbook. General Clippings 1983 (Volume 45)
- Scrapbook. General Clippings 1984 (Volume 46)
- Scrapbook. General Clippings 1985 (Volume 47)
- Scrapbook. General Clippings 1986 Jan - 1986 July (Volume 48)